<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    
    <title>Home</title>
    
    
    <link></link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>O que é um Invited Review?</title>
        <description>
          
          Ultimamente recebemos no Brazilian Journal of Geology (BJGEO) alguns pedidos de autores interessados em enviar artigos de revisão, os “Invited Reviews”. Mas o que é esse tipo de artigo? Uma revisão bibliográfica de tese pode ser publicada dessa maneira? Vamos ver: O BJGEO prevê, em seu escopo, a publicação de...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/bjgeo_rev_papers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/bjgeo_rev_papers/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UTM 23S??</title>
        <description>
          A common cartographical mistake in articles - 
          If there’s one thing that I see all the time as a reviewer, is a map of some study area in Brazil with a caption like “UTM coordinates zone 23S”. Don’t do that. Why? I’ll tell you. The UTM system divides the Earth into 60 zones (or fuses) of 6°...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/utm_23s/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/utm_23s/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>FAQ about BJGEO</title>
        <description>
          
          The Brazilian Journal of Geology is the official publication of the Brazilian Geological Society. As the Deputy Editor, I receive emails with common questions about the journal. So I decided to crate a page with some useful information for potential authors. Click here to go to the BJGEO FAQ page...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/faq_bjgeo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/faq_bjgeo/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tutorial - São Paulo City LiDAR</title>
        <description>
          
          The São Paulo City Hall has just released free LiDAR data covering the city on their digital mapping platform, GeoSampa. Since the GeoSampa site is in Portuguese, I posted a short tutorial on how to access the data in the SPAMLab blog: https://spamlab.github.io/2019-11-25-pmsp_laz/. Also, just a few hours after the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/pmsp_laz/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/pmsp_laz/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New site layout</title>
        <description>
          
          If you are reading this it means my website is… alive and well! And you can see that this website has changed a bit. It loads faster, the visual is different (cleaner, I hope) and it works on all screen sizes (well, maybe not on a Nokia 3310). The reason...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/new-layout/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/new-layout/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The SPAMLab has a website (and a blog)</title>
        <description>
          
          Yes, that’s right. I finally managed to get the SPAMLab website up and running. It’s hosted on Github Pages: SPAMLab.github.io I’ll try to keep it updated with our research projects and activities. Stay tuned, and follow us on Twitter (@spamlab.iee) and Instagram (@spamlab.iee).

        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/the-spamlab-has-a-website-and-a-blog/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/the-spamlab-has-a-website-and-a-blog/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Publish anything with us (just need to pay 1200 Euros)</title>
        <description>
          
          So I just got this email: Dear Dr. Grohmann, This is a follow up email regarding your invitation to write a chapter for a new Open Access book on “Multidimensional Flow Cytometry Techniques for Novel Highly Informative Assays,” edited by Dr. Marica Gemei. With over 2,800 titles published and a...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/publish-anything-with-us-just-need-to-pay-1200-euros/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/publish-anything-with-us-just-need-to-pay-1200-euros/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I deleted my account at Academia.edu</title>
        <description>
          
          I decided to delete my account at Academia.edu after reading Sarah Bond’s article in Forbes and Ethan Gruber’s post.

I’m thinking about hosting the PDFs of my papers and other documents with Zenodo or figshare (I already have some docs there). 

        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/i-deleted-my-account-at-academia-edu/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/i-deleted-my-account-at-academia-edu/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Denoising SRTM with GRASS-GIS</title>
        <description>
          
          Digital elevation data usually has some noise in it, but removing that noise may not be as easy as a simple filtering procedure. Using raster filters (mean, mode etc) in moving-windows operations will smooth the original topography. One solution is to perform the filtering with the XYZ information of each...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/denoise-srtm-grass/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/denoise-srtm-grass/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Curso Internacional de Espeleoresgate 2016</title>
        <description>
          
          Estão abertas as inscrições para o Curso Internacional de Espeleoresgate 2016. O curso é organizado pelo Grupo Bambuí de Pesquisas Espeleológicas em conjunto com a Federação Francesa de Espeleologia (FFS) e o Espeleo Socorro da França (SSF), com apoio do Espeleo Grupo de Brasília (EBG) e Meandros Espeleo Clube. O curso será...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/curso-internacional-de-espeleoresgate-2016/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/curso-internacional-de-espeleoresgate-2016/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Installing Orfeo Toolbox and Monteverdi on OSX</title>
        <description>
          
          The Orfeo ToolBox (OTB) is an open-source C++ library for processing of remote sensing image, and it is shipped with Monteverdi, an end-users oriented software for for classical remote sensing tasks. With the recent release of OTB version 5.4, I decided to make this brief post on how to get...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/installing-orfeo-toolbox-and-monteverdi-on-osx/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/installing-orfeo-toolbox-and-monteverdi-on-osx/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>O uso adequado de algumas expressões de tecnologia em inglês</title>
        <description>
          
          Reproduzo aqui um infográfico produzido pela iinterativa e publicado em followthecolours.com.br. Descobri graças ao Twitter do SIBI-USP. O infográfico é muito útil pois traz o uso correto de alguns termos em inglês ligados à tecnologia, como “on-line”, “e-mail” e o bem brasileiro “pen drive” (raramente usado pelos que falam inglês...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/o-uso-adequado-de-algumas-expressoes-de-tecnologia-em-ingles/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/o-uso-adequado-de-algumas-expressoes-de-tecnologia-em-ingles/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SRTM - erros frequentes e como evitá-los</title>
        <description>
          
          Os modelos de elevação SRTM são muito utilizados aqui no Brasil, já que não temos uma cobertura de mapas topográficos em escala decente (1:50.000 ou melhor) da maior parte de nosso território. Porém, tenho notado quatro erros muito frequentes nos artigos e monografias (TCCs, dissertações e teses) que vou comentar...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/srtm-erros-frequentes-e-como-evita-los/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/srtm-erros-frequentes-e-como-evita-los/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Relato de acidente e resgate - Lapa da Deuza (Vazante, MG)</title>
        <description>
          
          Em setembro de 2015, durante as atividades do curso de espeleo resgate em Mambaí (GO), recebemos a notícia que nosso amigo Ezio Rubbioli havia sofrido um acidente durante uma exploração na Lapa da Deuza (Vazante - MG). Felizmente tudo acabou bem e o resgate foi efetuado rapidamente. A seguir, reproduzo...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/acidente-ezio/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/acidente-ezio/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prof. Carlos Grohmann, mas pode chamar de 0000-0001-5073-5572</title>
        <description>
          
          Demorou mas finalmente está-se falando do ORCID aqui no Brasil. OR-quem? Calma que eu explico. ORCID é a sigla para Open Researcher and Contributor ID. A ideia é que cada pesquisador que se cadastra recebe um número de identificação (o meu é 0000-0001-5073-5572) e esse número é eterno. A pessoa...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/post_orcid/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/post_orcid/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Termos acadêmicos (português-inglês)</title>
        <description>
          
          Hoje achei uma lista bem interessante de termos utilizados na Academia e suas traduções em inglês. O original está aqui. A lista é claramente voltada ao inglês dos EUA, e encontrei alguns termos traduzidos incorretamente. Por exemplo, enquanto que no Brasil defende-se uma Dissertação de Mestrado e uma Tese de...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/termos-academicos-portugues-ingles/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/termos-academicos-portugues-ingles/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Working with GRASS-7.0 and homebrew python on OS X</title>
        <description>
          
          Sometimes getting all the software you need for Scientific analysis updated and running smoothly in OS X can be a bit annoying. For most things, there’s Homebrew (a nice post on setting your Mac for Scientific analysis with Python and homebrew is this one.) And if you’re into GIS, you...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/grass-brew-python-osx/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/grass-brew-python-osx/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>resample and derive or derive and resample? [paper review]</title>
        <description>
          
          Working with Digital Elevation Models (DEMs) have became a standard practice in scientific disciplines related to the physical environment, from geomorphology, geology, to biogeography and climate modeling. The Shuttle Radar Topography Mission (SRTM - Farr et al., 2007) and ASTER GDEM (Tachikawa et al., 2011) provide a near-global to global...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/regional-scale-analysis-of-dems-resample-and-derive-or-derive-and-resample-paper-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/regional-scale-analysis-of-dems-resample-and-derive-or-derive-and-resample-paper-review/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Curso de Espeleo Resgate - Mambaí, GO</title>
        <description>
          
          Entre 06 e 13 de setembro deste ano (2015, caso você esteja lendo do futuro) ocorreu mais uma edição do Curso de Formação em Espeleo Resgate, em parceira com o Espeleo Socorro Francês SSF - Spéléo Secours Français. O curso foi organizado (e muito bem organizado) pelos nossos amigos do...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/espeleo-resgate-mambai/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/espeleo-resgate-mambai/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Expedição Serra do Aracá 2015</title>
        <description>
          
          Durante 15 dias em julho/2015 o Grupo Bambuí de Pesquisas Espeleológicas (GBPE) em conjunto com o La Venta Esplorazioni Geografiche organizaram uma expedição de exploração espeleológica/geográfica na Serra do Aracá, norte do Estado do Amazonas. A equipe contou com cinco brasileiros e quatro italianos: Ezio Rubbioli (Bambuí) Alexandre Lobo (Bambuí) Daniel...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/expedicao-serra-do-araca-2015/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/expedicao-serra-do-araca-2015/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
